

## laurenmcelaney.design

linkedin.com/in/laurenmcelaney

mcelaneyl@gmail.com

818-568-6580

# LAUREN MCELANEY

# **SUMMARY**

I am a UI/UX Designer proficient in multimedia design and web design. I have experience in studying user behaviors which have allowed me to develop my skills with application development. I also have a strong background/interest in product design.

# **SKILLS**

Wireframing & Prototyping

Frontend Development

**Usability Testing** 

**Product Strategy** 

User Research & Testing

Persona & User Stories

Visual Design

UI/UX Design

# **TOOLS**

Figma

Sketch

Invision

Github

HTML & CSS

PHP

Adobe Creative Suite

**Usability Hub** 

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Web Designer

Freelance, 2015-Present

- · Designed and developed various websites, writing HTML, PHP, and CSS
- · Delievered high-quality graphics for both print and web

# Lauren Jeanne Photography 2007-2020

- · Founded fashion photography business
- · Assigned various test photo shoots for modeling agencies

## **Sole Society**

Style and Service Specialist, 2017-2018

- · Provided customer support via emails, phone, and chat
- · Assisted on multiple projects throughout departments

#### **Thrive Market**

Member Services Specialist, 2017

- · Frontline representation of the company
- · Monitored all social media platforms
- · Solving all customer service requests in a high call and email environment

## **Poolside Concierge**

Web Designer, 2009-2011

- · Created and managed website content
- Worked with the owner to recommend web copy for a target audience
- · Updated entire site three times to account for expanding product and territory needs

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Bloc

User Experience Design Program, 2018-2019

Online program teaching the core principles of UI/UX design as well as frontend development for both desktop and mobile.

#### Parsons

BFA Photography, 2015

# **RECENT PROJECTS**

#### In The Cloud

Cloud based storage application.

### Role:

- ·UI/UX
- ·Branding & Identity
- ·Visual Design

#### Solace

Mental health online community.

#### Role:

- ·UI/UX
- ·Branding & Identity
- ·Visual Design